Benjamin D. Killeen

Ph.D. Student, Johns Hopkins University Department of Computer Science 3400 N Charles St Baltimore, MD 21218, USA killeen@jhu.edu

🤗 benjamindkilleen.com - 🚢 arcade.cs.jhu.edu - 😩 cirl.lcsr.jhu.edu 🖙 Benjamin D. Killeen - 🏮 0000-0003-2511-7929 - 🗘 benjamindkilleen - 🎔 ®bdkilleen

Summary

A Ph.D. Student at Johns Hopkins University, I am a member of the Advanced Robotics and Interests Computationally Augmented Environments (ARCADE) research group and the Computational Interaction and Robotics Laboratory (CIRL). My research interests include computer vision, machine learning, and domain generalization, focusing on applications in robotic manipulation, medical imaging, and surgical robotics.

Education

 Ph.D., Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.
 08/2019 - present

 With Mathias Unberath and Gregory D. Hager.
 8.A., Computer Science with Honors, Physics Minor, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.
 09/2015 - 06/2019

Thesis: Starting from Scratch: Deep Learning for Novel Scientific Image Analysis

With Gordon Kindlmann.

Research Experience

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.

08/2020 - present With Mathias Unberath, Gregory D. Hager.

Research Assistant, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, 08/2019 - 06/2020 MD, USA.

With Gregory D. Hager, Mathias Unberath, and Russel Taylor. Recipient: LCSR Fellowship for Outstanding Incoming Ph.D. Students.

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicao, IL, USA. 03/2018 - 08/2019 With Gordon Kindlmann.

Professional Experience

Computer Vision / Al Intern, Applied Research, Intuitive Surgical Inc., Sunnyvale, CA, USA.

06/2020 - 07/2020

With Omid Mohareri.

Software Development Intern, Cognitive Computing, Epic Systems, Verona, WI, USA.

Research Intern, IBM Research - Almaden, San Jose, CA, USA.

With Geoffry Burr.

Selected Honors

Best Graduate Project Award, Computer Integrated Surgical Systems and Technology course, Johns Hopkins
University, USA.

COVID-19 Dataset Award, Kaggle
For our county-level dataset in [M-1].

05/2020

Intuitive Surgical Best Project Award, Deep Learning course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.

12/2019
Project: Enriching Unsupervised Feature Learning via Intermediate Subtasks.

With Michael Peven, Shaoyan Pan, Matthew Pittman.

Publications

My publication list is also available on Google Scholar.

Peer-reviewed

Journal Articles

A. Hundt, **B. D. Killeen**, H. Kwon, C. Paxton, GD Hager. "Good Robot!": Efficient Reinforcement Learning for Multi-Step Visual Tasks with Sim to Real Transfer. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol. 5, no. 4, pp. 6724–6731, Oct. 2020. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2020.3015448.

J-1

C-1

S. Ambrogio, P. Narayanan, H. Tsai, R. M. Shelby, I. Boybat, C. di Nolfo, S. Sidler, M. Giordano, M. Bodini, N. Farinha, **B. D. Killeen**, C. Cheng, Y. Jaoudi, G. W. Burr. Equivalent-accuracy accelerated neural-network training using analogue memory. Nature, vol. 558, no. 7708, p. 60, Jun. 2018. doi: 10.1038/s41586-018-0180-5.

Peer-reviewed

Conference Papers

C. Gao, X. Liu, W. Gu, **B. D. Killeen**, M. Armand, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Generalizing Spatial Transformers to Projective Geometry with Applications to 2D/3D Registration. MICCAI **(to appear)**, 2020.

X. Liu, Y. Zhang, **B. Killeen**, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Extremely Dense Point Correspondences using a Learned Feature Descriptor. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, pp. 4847-4856, 2020.

J. Y. Wu*, **B. D. Killeen***, P. Nikutta, M. Thies, A. Zapaishchykova, S. Chakraborty, M. Unberath Changes in M-2 Reproductive Rate of SARS-CoV-2 Due to Non-pharmaceutical Interventions in 1,417 U.S. Counties. medRxiv preprint, Jun. 2020, doi: 10.1101/2020.05.31.20118687. *Equal contribution. B. D. Killeen, J. Y. Wu, K. Shah, A. Zapaishchykova, P. Nikutta, A. Tamhane, S. Chakraborty, J. Wei, T. Gao, M. M-1 Thies, M. Unberath. A County-level Dataset for Informing the United States' Response to COVID-19. arXiv preprint, 2020, arXiv:2004.00756. G. W. Burr and B. D. Killeen. 2020. Efficient Processing of Convolutional Neural Network Layers Using Analog-P-1 memory-based Hardware. 20200117986, filed March 25, 2019, and issued April 16, 2020. https://uspto.report/patent/app/20200117986. Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, 03/2019 - 06/2019 Chicago, IL, USA With Prof. Yali Amit. Wrote supplementary course material and held weekly lab sessions. Link: github.com/benjamindkilleen/lsda Selected review: "Ben was incredibly patient during office hours and always responsive to student questions. In addition, he often presented demos during office hours or showed easier ways to handle the homework assignments; both were very helpful." More reviews available at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2019-spring-lsda 01/2019 - 08/2019 Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA - Scientific Visualization - Introduction to Computer Science I - Introduction to Computer Science II Topics in Machine Learning, Baltimore, MD, USA. 06/2020 - present I tutor young people (middle- and high-school age) who are interested in CS and ML. More info at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2020-tutoring. Nonlinear Optimization II Computer Integrated Surgery II Computer Integrated Surgery I Deep Learning GPA: 3.81 Unsupervised Learning* Computer Vision Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis Operating Systems Honors Combinatorics Honors Algorithms Honors Discrete Mathematics Scientific Visualization Programming Languages Networks and Distributed Systems

Undergraduate

Selected Coursework

Patents

Teaching Assistant Teaching

Grading

Tutoring

Graduate

*Graduate level.

Creative Interests

Creative nonfiction: benjamindkilleen.com/blog Science Fiction: novel available by request.

Metadata

This document is available for download at benjamindkilleen.com/files/cv.pdf.

Last updated: September 2020